<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Python Decorators I Use in Almost All My Data Science Projects</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-5-python-decorators-i-use-in-almost-all-my-data-science-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-5-python-decorators-i-use-in-almost-all-my-data-science-projects/</guid>
      <description>Decorators provide a new and convenient way for everything from caching to sending notifications
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Quantum Natural Language Processing </title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-a-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-natural-language-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-a-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-natural-language-processing/</guid>
      <description>In this introduction to Quantum Natural Language Processing (QNLP), we will see how words&#39; meaning is classically encoded into computers. We will then discuss the challenges representing the meaning of sentences, and present a framework to achieve it (DisCoCat). After seeing that this method benefits a quantum speedup, we will present three examples of use cases.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing OpenChatKit</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-announcing-openchatkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-announcing-openchatkit/</guid>
      <description>OpenChatKit provides a powerful, open-source base to create both specialized and general purpose chatbots for various applications. We collaborated with LAION and Ontocord to create the training dataset. Much more than a model release, this is the beginning of an open source project. We are releasing a set of tools and processes for ongoing improvement with community contributions.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Chat Dapp | Build Decentralize Chat Application On Ethereum </title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-blockchain-chat-dapp-build-decentralize-chat-application-on-ethereum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-blockchain-chat-dapp-build-decentralize-chat-application-on-ethereum/</guid>
      <description>This blockchain chat app is powered by smart contracts run on the #Ethereum blockchain using an avalanche text network, In this blockchain chap Dapp or decentralized chat application is one of the projects which you can include in your blockchain project portfolio.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Web3 DEX | FULL COURSE | React, Node, Moralis, 1Inch</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-build-a-web3-dex-full-course-react-node-moralis-1inch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-build-a-web3-dex-full-course-react-node-moralis-1inch/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we build a fully functional Web3 Decentralized Exchange, from start to finish. It will allow users to swap erc20 tokens to other erc20 tokens on a selected EVM Chain.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy a Web3 Blockchain Crowdfunding Platform</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-build-and-deploy-a-web3-blockchain-crowdfunding-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-build-and-deploy-a-web3-blockchain-crowdfunding-platform/</guid>
      <description>With a stunning design, connected to the blockchain, metamask pairing, interaction with smart contracts, sending Ethereum through the blockchain network, writing solidity code, and, most importantly, the ability to create create, view, and donate to crowdfunding campaigns directly through the blockchain; this course is perfect to fully understand how web3, blockchain, Solidity, and smart contracts truly work behind the scenes.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect OpenAI To &#43;5,000 Tools (LangChain &#43; Zapier)</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-connect-openai-to-5-000-tools-langchain-zapier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-connect-openai-to-5-000-tools-langchain-zapier/</guid>
      <description>Connect OpenAI To +5,000 Tools (LangChain + Zapier)
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Moderation &amp; Fraud Detection - Patterns in Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-content-moderation-fraud-detection-patterns-in-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-content-moderation-fraud-detection-patterns-in-industry/</guid>
      <description>Content moderation is the process of learning and inferring the quality of human-generated content such as product reviews, social media posts, and ads. How do we know which are irrelevant, incorrect, or downright harmful? A related problem is detecting anomalous activity such as fraudulent transactions or malicious traffic.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3: An Automated System to Detect Data Drifts</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-d3-an-automated-system-to-detect-data-drifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-d3-an-automated-system-to-detect-data-drifts/</guid>
      <description>Data powers almost all critical, customer-facing flows at Uber. Bad data quality impacts our ML models, leading to a bad user experience (incorrect fares, ETAs, products, etc.) and revenue loss.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATABUTTON - Your full (stack) potential has arrived</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-databutton-your-full-stack-potential-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-databutton-your-full-stack-potential-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve built a space where data skills and creativity are all you need to build insanely powerful full stack data apps.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of the New Cohere Summarization Endpoint</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-discovery-of-the-new-cohere-summarization-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-discovery-of-the-new-cohere-summarization-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, Cohere.ai announced their new dedicated summarization endpoint! For someone currently doing their PhD on text summarization, this is both worrying, but obviously also a rather intriguing development: while recent advancements have been focusing on rather broadly applicable models (think, chatGPT), providing more task-specific alternatives seems to be the niche that Cohere is carving out for themselves.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT 4: Superpower results with search</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-gpt-4-superpower-results-with-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-gpt-4-superpower-results-with-search/</guid>
      <description>GPT-4 is pretty incredible, but like its predecessors, it has problems. Hallucinations and the lack of up-to-date information are typical of Large Language Models (LLMs), from PaLM and LLaMa, to ChatGPT (gpt-3.5-turbo) and GPT 4.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Notion ChatBot For Your Knowledge Base Using LangChain</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-how-to-build-a-notion-chatbot-for-your-knowledge-base-using-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-how-to-build-a-notion-chatbot-for-your-knowledge-base-using-langchain/</guid>
      <description>In this video we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create a simple chatbot to question-answer your Notion knowledge base using Typescript, LangChain and Pinecone.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Papers Explained</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-ml-papers-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-ml-papers-explained/</guid>
      <description>Explanations to key concepts in ML
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ModelScope is built upon the notion of “Model-as-a-Service” (MaaS)</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-modelscope-is-built-upon-the-notion-of-model-as-a-service-maas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-modelscope-is-built-upon-the-notion-of-model-as-a-service-maas/</guid>
      <description>ModelScope is built upon the notion of “Model-as-a-Service” (MaaS). It seeks to bring together most advanced machine learning models from the AI community, and streamlines the process of leveraging AI models in real-world applications. The core ModelScope library open-sourced in this repository provides the interfaces and implementations that allow developers to perform model inference, training and evaluation.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Theory</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-network-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-network-theory/</guid>
      <description>Scientists and engineers use diagrams of networks in many different ways. Together with many collaborators I am studying networks with the tools of modern mathematics, such as category theory. You can read blog articles, papers and a book about our research. I am collaborating with the Topos Institute to use the resulting math for scientific computation, such as quickly adaptable models of infectious disease.
Link
The Mathematics of Networks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenPose has represented the first real-time multi-person system to jointly detect human body</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-openpose-has-represented-the-first-real-time-multi-person-system-to-jointly-detect-human-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-openpose-has-represented-the-first-real-time-multi-person-system-to-jointly-detect-human-body/</guid>
      <description>OpenPose has represented the first real-time multi-person system to jointly detect human body, hand, facial, and foot keypoints (in total 135 keypoints) on single images.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenXLA is available now to accelerate and simplify machine learning</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-openxla-is-available-now-to-accelerate-and-simplify-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-openxla-is-available-now-to-accelerate-and-simplify-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>ML development and deployment today suffer from fragmented and siloed infrastructure that can differ by framework, hardware, and use case. Such fragmentation restrains developer velocity and imposes barriers to model portability, efficiency, and productionization.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyXAB - Python X-Armed Bandit</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-pyxab-python-x-armed-bandit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-pyxab-python-x-armed-bandit/</guid>
      <description>PyXAB is a Python open-source library for X-armed bandit algorithms, a prestigious set of optimizers for online black-box optimization, i.e., optimize an objective without gradients, also known as the continuous-arm bandit (CAB), Lipschitz bandit, global optimization (GO) and bandit-based black-box optimization problems.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REPLIT - Make something great</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-17-replit-make-something-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-17-replit-make-something-great/</guid>
      <description>Build software collaboratively with the power of AI, on any device, without spending a second on setup
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
