<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>7 Most Starred Python Library You Should Know</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-7-most-starred-python-library-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-7-most-starred-python-library-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>Power up your Python development
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate ML model retraining and deployment with MLflow in Databricks</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-automate-ml-model-retraining-and-deployment-with-mlflow-in-databricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-automate-ml-model-retraining-and-deployment-with-mlflow-in-databricks/</guid>
      <description>Getting a working machine learning model deployed for user consumption is a great achievement. We see statistics showing that machine learning models often fail to make it into production, whether this is due to insufficient data, lack of direction or other reasons.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best ChatGPT Prompt Generator</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-best-chatgpt-prompt-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-best-chatgpt-prompt-generator/</guid>
      <description>Best ChatGPT Prompt Generator
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Dune Analytics with Uniswap</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-blockchain-dune-analytics-with-uniswap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-blockchain-dune-analytics-with-uniswap/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain Dune Analytics with Uniswap
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build No-Code AI Apps</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-build-no-code-ai-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-build-no-code-ai-apps/</guid>
      <description>Hubble is a powerful no-code platform for creating AI-enabled applications with no engineers.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Machine Learning Platform [Definitive Guide]</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-building-a-machine-learning-platform-definitive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-building-a-machine-learning-platform-definitive-guide/</guid>
      <description>Moving across the typical machine learning lifecycle can be a nightmare. From gathering and processing data to building models through experiments, deploying the best ones, and managing them at scale for continuous value in production—it’s a lot.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chart Gallery</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-chart-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-chart-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Each chart shown below is a QuickChart image built with a Chart.js config. These images can be sent in emails or embedded in any platform.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT x Botpress: unleash generative AI to build the next generation of chatbots</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-chatgpt-x-botpress-unleash-generative-ai-to-build-the-next-generation-of-chatbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-chatgpt-x-botpress-unleash-generative-ai-to-build-the-next-generation-of-chatbots/</guid>
      <description>ChatGPT has reimagined the possibilities for chatbots! This webinar will show you how Botpress is reinventing the entire bot-building process with generative AI.
[Link](ChatGPT has reimagined the possibilities for chatbots! This webinar will show you how Botpress is reinventing the entire bot-building process with generative AI.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust Platform Documentation</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-dust-platform-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-dust-platform-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Use the Dust Platform to design and deploy Large Language Model apps
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixie Developer Portal</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-fixie-developer-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-fixie-developer-portal/</guid>
      <description>Fixie is a platform for building applications using Large Language Models. With Fixie, you can write apps that communicate, in natural language, with one or more Agents that can access individual APIs or sources of data, such as GitHub, Google Calendar, or a database.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation Model Ops: Powering the Next Wave of Generative AI Apps</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-foundation-model-ops-powering-the-next-wave-of-generative-ai-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-foundation-model-ops-powering-the-next-wave-of-generative-ai-apps/</guid>
      <description>Late last year, we published our framework for the enterprise AI stack and gestured toward the potential of foundation models to advance innovation at each of its layers, from AI-optimized hardware, compute, and cloud on up. Yesterday’s release of GPT-4, with its ability to process both text and image inputs, promises to accelerate this paradigm shift in AI, which dramatically reduces the time, technical knowledge, and cost needed to spin up AI-enhanced products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPT-4 API with streaming responses, chat history, streamlit, gradio UI, JavaScript, FastAPI webapp</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-gpt-4-api-with-streaming-responses-chat-history-streamlit-gradio-ui-javascript-fastapi-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-gpt-4-api-with-streaming-responses-chat-history-streamlit-gradio-ui-javascript-fastapi-webapp/</guid>
      <description>This video will explain how to use GPT-4 api, create an evolving chat history which respects token context limits by droppping earlier conversation when necessary. We will also learn about how to stream responses to the terminal and with the Steramlit UI. We will build two different gradio UIs and also a webapp using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and FastAPI.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a Chatbot with ChatGPT API and a Conversational Memory in Python</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-how-to-build-a-chatbot-with-chatgpt-api-and-a-conversational-memory-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-how-to-build-a-chatbot-with-chatgpt-api-and-a-conversational-memory-in-python/</guid>
      <description>With the emergence of Large Language Models (LLMs), AI technologies have advanced to a level where humans can converse with chatbots in a way that resembles human conversation. In my opinion, chatbots are poised to become an essential component of our daily lives for a wide range of problem-solving tasks. We will soon encounter chatbots in various domains, including customer service and personal assistance.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy Diffusers in the cloud</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-how-to-deploy-diffusers-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-how-to-deploy-diffusers-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>How to deploy Diffusers in the cloud
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn anything</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-learn-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-learn-anything/</guid>
      <description>Try topics like physics, american history, or your own name!
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>react-admin</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-react-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-react-admin/</guid>
      <description>A frontend Framework for building data-driven applications running in the browser on top of REST/GraphQL APIs, using ES6, React and Material Design. Open sourced and maintained by marmelab.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training large language models on Amazon SageMaker: Best practices</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-25-training-large-language-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-25-training-large-language-models-on-amazon-sagemaker-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Language models are statistical methods predicting the succession of tokens in sequences, using natural text. Large language models (LLMs) are neural network-based language models with hundreds of millions (BERT) to over a trillion parameters (MiCS), and whose size makes single-GPU training impractical. LLMs’ generative abilities make them popular for text synthesis, summarization, machine translation, and more.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Generated Stories (AWS)</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-19-ai-generated-stories-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-19-ai-generated-stories-aws/</guid>
      <description>Example open source event-driven application that generates a new bed time story for your children every night using Lambda, EventBridge, DynamoDB, App Runner, ChatGPT and DALL-E.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Application Composer Now Generally Available – Visually Build Serverless Applications Quickly</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-19-aws-application-composer-now-generally-available-visually-build-serverless-applications-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-19-aws-application-composer-now-generally-available-visually-build-serverless-applications-quickly/</guid>
      <description>At AWS re:Invent 2022, we previewed AWS Application Composer, a visual builder for you to compose and configure serverless applications from AWS services backed by deployment-ready infrastructure as code (IaC).
Link
Visually design and build serverless applications| Serverless Office Hours</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Clone – OpenAI API and React Tutorial</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-19-chatgpt-clone-openai-api-and-react-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-03-19-chatgpt-clone-openai-api-and-react-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use React and the OpenAI API to create an application like ChatGPT. The application can answer our questions, convert the text into different languages, or even convert JavaScript code to Python.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
