<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Algebra, Topology, Differential Calculus, and Optimization Theory For Computer Science and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-algebra-topology-differential-calculus-and-optimization-theory-for-computer-science-and-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-algebra-topology-differential-calculus-and-optimization-theory-for-computer-science-and-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Algebra, Topology, Differential Calculus, and Optimization Theory For Computer Science and Machine Learning
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An easy-to-use &amp; supercharged open-source experiment tracker</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-an-easy-to-use-supercharged-open-source-experiment-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-an-easy-to-use-supercharged-open-source-experiment-tracker/</guid>
      <description>Aim logs your training runs, enables a beautiful UI to compare them and an API to query them programmatically.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Production Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-awesome-production-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-awesome-production-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>This repository contains a curated list of awesome open source libraries that will help you deploy, monitor, version, scale and secure your production machine learning
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captum - Model Interpretability for PyTorch</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-captum-model-interpretability-for-pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-captum-model-interpretability-for-pytorch/</guid>
      <description>Captum (“comprehension” in Latin) is an open source, extensible library for model interpretability built on PyTorch.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 230 ― Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-cs-230-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-cs-230-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Set of illustrated Deep Learning cheatsheets covering the content of the CS 230 class
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATA MESH ARCHITECTURE</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-data-mesh-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-data-mesh-architecture/</guid>
      <description>The term data mesh was coined by Zhamak Dehghani in 2019 and is based on four fundamental principles that bundle well-known concepts
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databolt Flow</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-databolt-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-databolt-flow/</guid>
      <description>For data scientists and data engineers, d6tflow is a python library which makes building complex data science workflows easy, fast and intuitive. It is primarily designed for data scientists to build better models faster. For data engineers, it can also be a lightweight alternative and help productionize data science models faster. Unlike other data pipeline/workflow solutions, d6tflow focuses on managing data science research workflows instead of managing production data pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started in the World of Stable Diffusion</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-getting-started-in-the-world-of-stable-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-getting-started-in-the-world-of-stable-diffusion/</guid>
      <description>In simple words, stable diffusion is a deep learning model that can generate an image given a prompt
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JINA - Build cross-modal and multi-modal applications on the cloud</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-jina-build-cross-modal-and-multi-modal-applications-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-jina-build-cross-modal-and-multi-modal-applications-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Jina is a MLOps framework that empowers anyone to build cross-modal and multi-modal applications on the cloud. It uplifts a PoC into a production-ready service. Jina handles the infrastructure complexity, making advanced solution engineering and cloud-native technologies accessible to every developer.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using graph neural networks to recommend related products</title>
      <link>/post/2022-11-05-using-graph-neural-networks-to-recommend-related-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-11-05-using-graph-neural-networks-to-recommend-related-products/</guid>
      <description>Recommending related products — say, a phone case to go along with a new phone — is a fundamental capability of e-commerce sites, one that saves customers time and leads to more satisfying shopping experiences.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A community maintained Python library for creating mathematical animations.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-a-community-maintained-python-library-for-creating-mathematical-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-a-community-maintained-python-library-for-creating-mathematical-animations/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A general-purpose programmatic animation tool</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-a-general-purpose-programmatic-animation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-a-general-purpose-programmatic-animation-tool/</guid>
      <description>A gallery of animations made with Morpho is available here. For more, you can also take a look at the YouTube channels Morphocular and Serpentine Integral, which use Morpho to create most of the animations.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome AI Guidelines</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-awesome-ai-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-awesome-ai-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>This repository aims to simplify this by mapping the ecosystem of guidelines, principles, codes of ethics, standards and regulation being put in place around artificial intelligence.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Realtime Chat App with Django Channels and WebSockets</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-building-a-realtime-chat-app-with-django-channels-and-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-building-a-realtime-chat-app-with-django-channels-and-websockets/</guid>
      <description>Building stateful web applications can be tricky, unless you use a framework, of course—Django to the rescue! In this article, learn how to build a realtime chat app using Django Channels and WebSockets.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building makemore Part 3: Activations &amp; Gradients, BatchNorm</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-building-makemore-part-3-activations-gradients-batchnorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-building-makemore-part-3-activations-gradients-batchnorm/</guid>
      <description>We dive into some of the internals of MLPs with multiple layers and scrutinize the statistics of the forward pass activations, backward pass gradients, and some of the pitfalls when they are improperly scaled. We also look at the typical diagnostic tools and visualizations you&amp;rsquo;d want to use to understand the health of your deep network. We learn why training deep neural nets can be fragile and introduce the first modern innovation that made doing so much easier: Batch Normalization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS197 Harvard: AI Research Experiences</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-cs197-harvard-ai-research-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-cs197-harvard-ai-research-experiences/</guid>
      <description>Once we go from training one model to training hundreds of different models with different hyperparameters, we need to start organizing. We’re going to break down our organization into three pieces: experiment tracking, hyperparameter search, and configuration setup.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How diffusion models work: the math from scratch</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-how-diffusion-models-work-the-math-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-how-diffusion-models-work-the-math-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion models are a new class of state-of-the-art generative models that generate diverse high-resolution images. They have already attracted a lot of attention after OpenAI, Nvidia and Google managed to train large-scale models. Example architectures that are based on diffusion models are GLIDE, DALLE-2, Imagen, and the full open-source stable diffusion.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>skopeo is a command line utility that performs various operations on container images and image repositories.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-skopeo-is-a-command-line-utility-that-performs-various-operations-on-container-images-and-image-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-skopeo-is-a-command-line-utility-that-performs-various-operations-on-container-images-and-image-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Skopeo works with API V2 container image registries such as docker.io and quay.io registries, private registries, local directories and local OCI-layout directories.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneaky REST APIs With Django Ninja</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-sneaky-rest-apis-with-django-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-sneaky-rest-apis-with-django-ninja/</guid>
      <description>Many web projects have moved to the single-page application model. To use this model with Django, you build a project where Django is the back end accessed through a REST API. The Django Ninja library is a FastAPI-inspired tool kit for turning Django views into REST API endpoints with very little extra code. Along the way, you’ll be using curl, a command-line tool that allows you to grab the contents of a web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacetimeformer Multivariate Forecasting</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-spacetimeformer-multivariate-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-spacetimeformer-multivariate-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Spacetimeformer is a Transformer that learns temporal patterns like a time series model and spatial patterns like a Graph Neural Network.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
