<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in datascienceblog.net: R for Data Science on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9 Incredible Websites That Every Developer Should Bookmark</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-9-incredible-websites-that-every-developer-should-bookmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-9-incredible-websites-that-every-developer-should-bookmark/</guid>
      <description>These websites will not only assist you in your software development journey but will also assist you in your content creation journey.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A library to inspect itermediate layers of PyTorch models.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-a-library-to-inspect-itermediate-layers-of-pytorch-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-a-library-to-inspect-itermediate-layers-of-pytorch-models/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s often the case that we want to inspect intermediate layers of a model without modifying the code e.g. visualize attention matrices of language models, get values from an intermediate layer to feed to another layer, or applying a loss function to intermediate layers.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple approach for background task in Django</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-a-simple-approach-for-background-task-in-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-a-simple-approach-for-background-task-in-django/</guid>
      <description>When there is a long running task, there are usually below 2 requirements:
As a user, I want to know the progress of the task As a user, I want to get the output of the task if it is finished We will use the out of the box features Threading and Cache in Python and Django respectively to achieve this
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Computer Vision with Python - Full Course</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-advanced-computer-vision-with-python-full-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-advanced-computer-vision-with-python-full-course/</guid>
      <description>Learn advanced computer vision using Python in this full course. You will learn state of the art computer vision techniques by building five projects with libraries such as OpenCV and Mediapipe. If you are a beginner, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of the term advance. Even though the concepts are advanced,
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatic 101</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-bioinformatic-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-bioinformatic-101/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Beautify </title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-code-beautify/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-code-beautify/</guid>
      <description>Code Formatter, JSON Beautifier, XML Viewer, Hex Converters and more&amp;hellip;
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CodeKeep - A Better Way to Organize , Share &amp; Discover Snippets</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-codekeep-a-better-way-to-organize-share-discover-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-codekeep-a-better-way-to-organize-share-discover-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS224N: Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning | Winter 2021</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-cs224n-natural-language-processing-with-deep-learning-winter-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-cs224n-natural-language-processing-with-deep-learning-winter-2021/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization 101</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-data-visualization-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-data-visualization-101/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DeepChem Step-by-Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-deepchem-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-deepchem-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial series, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to use DeepChem to solve interesting and challenging problems in the life sciences. The tutorial acts as a introduction to DeepChem as well as application of DeepChem to a wide array of problems across domains like molecular machine learning, quantum chemistry, bioinformatics and material science. This tutorial series is continually updated with new DeepChem features and models as implemented and is designed to be accessible to beginners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FastAPI Celery, Flower and Docker</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-fastapi-celery-flower-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-fastapi-celery-flower-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we integrate Celery into an existing FastAPI app, Redis and FastAPI, all within Docker containers. We finish off by implementing Flower to monitor Celery jobs and workers.
Link
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HashiCorp Terraform Associate Certification Course - Pass the Exam!</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-hashicorp-terraform-associate-certification-course-pass-the-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-hashicorp-terraform-associate-certification-course-pass-the-exam/</guid>
      <description>Prepare for the HashiCorp Terraform Associate Certification and pass! The Terraform Associate certification is for Cloud Engineers specializing in operations, IT, or development who know the basic concepts and skills associated with open source HashiCorp Terraform.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugging Face Transformers Amazon SageMaker Examples</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-hugging-face-transformers-amazon-sagemaker-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-hugging-face-transformers-amazon-sagemaker-examples/</guid>
      <description>Example Jupyter notebooks that demonstrate how to build, train, and deploy Hugging Face Transformers using Amazon SageMaker and the Amazon SageMaker Python SDK.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstart Your Development Journey With the Smart Contract Starter Kit</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-kickstart-your-development-journey-with-the-smart-contract-starter-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-kickstart-your-development-journey-with-the-smart-contract-starter-kit/</guid>
      <description>If you’re looking for a starting point to learn smart contract development, the Smart Contract Starter Kit is the place to go. You can access tests, scripts, deployments, and more, and it covers all of the key frameworks, including Brownie, dAppTools, Foundry, Hardhat, Solana, and Truffle.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning sample apps</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-machine-learning-sample-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-machine-learning-sample-apps/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning sample apps - this repo provides sample code to support my articles on Towards Data Science and Youtube channel.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize PyTorch Performance for Speed and Memory Efficiency </title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-optimize-pytorch-performance-for-speed-and-memory-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-optimize-pytorch-performance-for-speed-and-memory-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>The training/inference processes of deep learning models are involved lots of steps. The faster each experiment iteration is, the more we can optimize the whole model prediction performance given limited time and resources. I collected and organized several PyTorch tricks and tips to maximize the efficiency of memory usage and minimize the run time. To better leverage these tips, we also need to understand how and why they work.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch and Monai for AI Healthcare Imaging - Python Machine Learning Course</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-pytorch-and-monai-for-ai-healthcare-imaging-python-machine-learning-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-pytorch-and-monai-for-ai-healthcare-imaging-python-machine-learning-course/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use PyTorch, Monai, and Python for computer vision using machine learning. One practical use-case for artificial intelligence is healthcare imaging. In this course, you will improve your machine learning skills by creating an algorithm for automatic liver segmentation.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Open Source libraries for data quality improvement</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-15-open-source-libraries-for-data-quality-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-15-open-source-libraries-for-data-quality-improvement/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips To Maximize PyTorch Performance</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-7-tips-to-maximize-pytorch-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-7-tips-to-maximize-pytorch-performance/</guid>
      <description>Throughout the last 10 months, while working on PyTorch Lightning, the team and I have been exposed to many styles of structuring PyTorch code and we have identified a few key places where we see people inadvertently introducing bottlenecks.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airtable</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-airtable/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-airtable/</guid>
      <description>Airtable’s intuitive yet powerful platform gives everyone the flexibility to create their own solution and make work flow faster.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
