<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Python Libraries for Time-Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-28-5-python-libraries-for-time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-28-5-python-libraries-for-time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Time-Series is a sequence of data points collected at different timestamps. 
These are essentially successive measurements collected from the same data source at the same time interval. Further, we can use these chronologically gathered readings to monitor trends and changes over time. The time-series models can be univariate or multivariate. 
The univariate time series models are implemented when the dependent variable is a single time series, like room temperature measurement from a single sensor. 
On the other hand, a multivariate time series model can be used when there are multiple dependent variables, i.e., the output depends on more than one series. An example for the multivariate time-series model could be modelling the GDP, inflation, and unemployment together as these variables are linked to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2022/05/5-python-libraries-for-time-series-analysis/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning sample apps</title>
      <link>/post/2022-05-02-machine-learning-sample-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-05-02-machine-learning-sample-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning sample apps - this repo provides sample code to support my articles on Towards Data Science and Youtube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/katanaml/sample-apps&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking the Right Questions: Training a T5 Transformer Model on a New task</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-asking-the-right-questions-training-a-t5-transformer-model-on-a-new-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-asking-the-right-questions-training-a-t5-transformer-model-on-a-new-task/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The T5 Transformer frames any NLP task as a text-to-text task enabling pre-trained models to easily learn new tasks. Let’s teach the old dog a new trick!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/asking-the-right-questions-training-a-t5-transformer-model-on-a-new-task-691ebba2d72c&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End AutoML Pipeline with H2O AutoML, MLflow, FastAPI, and Streamlit</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-end-to-end-automl-pipeline-with-h2o-automl-mlflow-fastapi-and-streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-end-to-end-automl-pipeline-with-h2o-automl-mlflow-fastapi-and-streamlit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An easy-to-follow comprehensive guide on using a stack of powerful tools to train and serve an AutoML pipeline for insurance cross-sell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/end-to-end-automl-train-and-serve-with-h2o-mlflow-fastapi-and-streamlit-5d36eedfe606&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommender Systems: Machine Learning Metrics and Business Metrics</title>
      <link>/post/2022-04-09-recommender-systems-machine-learning-metrics-and-business-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-04-09-recommender-systems-machine-learning-metrics-and-business-metrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will start by discussing what recommender systems are and what are their applications and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also compare the main techniques of building machine learning models for recommender systems and take a look at metrics and business evaluation techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are going to see how to choose these metrics for the required evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architectures Powering Machine Learning at Google, Facebook, Uber, LinkedIn</title>
      <link>/post/2022-02-19-the-architectures-powering-machine-learning-at-google-facebook-uber-linkedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-02-19-the-architectures-powering-machine-learning-at-google-facebook-uber-linkedin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge of establishing reference architectures for large-scale machine learning solutions is accentuated by two main factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine learning frameworks and infrastructure have evolved considerably faster than the adoption of those technologies in mainstream environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lifecycle of machine learning solutions is fundamentally different from other software disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@goutambiswas/the-architectures-powering-machine-learning-at-google-facebook-uber-linkedin-c28e8da9b782&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph for Job Search Using BERT</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will build a job recommendation and skill discovery script that will take unstructured text as input, and will then output job recommendations and skill suggestions based on entities such as skills, years of experience, diploma, and major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will extract entities and relations from job descriptions using the BERT model and we will attempt to build a knowledge graph from skills and years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/06/knowledge-graph-job-search-bert.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Machine Learning with Python Part 1: Basics, Metrics, and Algorithms</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-1-basics-metrics-and-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-1-basics-metrics-and-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An introduction to networks via key metrics and algorithms on a Football dataset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/graph-machine-learning-with-python-pt-1-basics-metrics-and-algorithms-cc40972de113&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Machine Learning with Python Part 2: Random Graphs and Diffusion Models of CryptoPunks Trading</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-2-random-graphs-and-diffusion-models-of-cryptopunks-trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-2-random-graphs-and-diffusion-models-of-cryptopunks-trading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simulating and modeling the CryptoPunks trading data via a graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/graph-machine-learning-with-python-pt-2-random-graphs-and-diffusion-models-of-cryptopunks-trading-99cd5170b5ea&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Knowledge Graph with Neo4J and Transformers</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to build a knowledge graph from job descriptions using fine-tuned transformer-based Named Entity Recognition (NER) and spacy’s relation extraction models. The method described here can be used in any different field such as biomedical, finance, healthcare, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the steps we are going to take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load our fine-tuned transformer NER and spacy relation extraction model in google colab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Neo4j Sandbox and add our entities and relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Query our graph to find the highest job match to a target resume, find the three most popular skills and highest skills co-occurrence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/11/build-knowledge-graph-neo4j-transformers.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Deploy a Simple Sentiment Analysis App via API</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FastAPI might be able to help. FastAPI is FastAPI is a web framework for building APIs with Python. We will use FastAPI in this article to build a REST API to service an NLP model which can be queried via GET request and can dole out responses to those queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example, we will skip the building of our own model, and instead leverage the Pipeline class of the HuggingFace Transformers library. Transformers is full of SOTA NLP models which can be used out of the box as-is, as well as fine-tuned for specific uses and high performance. The library&amp;rsquo;s pipelines can be summed up as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipelines are a great and easy way to use models for inference. These pipelines are objects that abstract most of the complex code from the library, offering a simple API dedicated to several tasks, including Named Entity Recognition, Masked Language Modeling, Sentiment Analysis, Feature Extraction and Question Answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Transformers library, FastAPI, and astonishingly little code, we are going to create and deploy a very simple sentiment analysis app. We will also see how extending this same approach to a more complex app would be quite straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/06/create-deploy-sentiment-analysis-app-api.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Metaflow</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Metaflow is a human-friendly Python library that helps scientists and engineers build and manage real-life data science projects. Metaflow was originally developed at Netflix to boost the productivity of data scientists who work on a wide variety of projects from classical statistics to state-of-the-art deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaflow provides a unified API to the infrastructure stack that is required to execute data science projects, from prototype to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.metaflow.org/introduction/what-is-metaflow&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Production Level Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-a-guide-to-production-level-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-a-guide-to-production-level-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploying deep learning models in production can be challenging, as it is far beyond training models with good performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several distinct components need to be designed and developed in order to deploy a production level deep learning system (seen below):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alirezadir/Production-Level-Deep-Learning&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/components.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome production machine learning</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-awesome-production-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-awesome-production-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a curated list of awesome open source libraries that will help you deploy, monitor, version, scale, and secure your production machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethicalml/awesome-production-machine-learning&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Software Engineering for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-awesome-software-engineering-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-awesome-software-engineering-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software Engineering for Machine Learning are techniques and guidelines for building ML applications that do not concern the core ML problem &amp;ndash; e.g. the development of new algorithms &amp;ndash; but rather the surrounding activities like data ingestion, coding, testing, versioning, deployment, quality control, and team collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good software engineering practices enhance development, deployment and maintenance of production level applications using machine learning components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SE-ML/awesome-seml&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Deploying a Machine Learning Model on Vertex AI using Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Write ML Pipelines that will make your MLOps team happy: follow a clean separation of responsibility between model code and ops code. This article show you how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python-865b535814f8&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EvalML</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-evalml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-evalml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EvalML is an AutoML library which builds, optimizes, and evaluates machine learning pipelines using domain-specific objective functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Functionality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automation - Makes machine learning easier. Avoid training and tuning models by hand. Includes data quality checks, cross-validation and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Checks - Catches and warns of problems with your data and problem setup before modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-to-end - Constructs and optimizes pipelines that include state-of-the-art preprocessing, feature engineering, feature selection, and a variety of modeling techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model Understanding - Provides tools to understand and introspect on models, to learn how they&amp;rsquo;ll behave in your problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain-specific - Includes repository of domain-specific objective functions and an interface to define your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explain Yourself - A Primer on ML Interpretability &amp; Explainability</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-explain-yourself-a-primer-on-ml-interpretability-explainability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-explain-yourself-a-primer-on-ml-interpretability-explainability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/content.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thegradient.pub/explain-yourself/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From model inception to deployment</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-from-model-inception-to-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-from-model-inception-to-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning model training &amp;amp; scalable deployment with Flask, Nginx &amp;amp; Gunicorn wrapped in a Docker Container&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/from-model-inception-to-deployment-adce1f5ed9d6&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugging Face Transformer Inference Under 1 Millisecond Latency</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-hugging-face-transformer-inference-under-1-millisecond-latency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-hugging-face-transformer-inference-under-1-millisecond-latency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/hugging-face-transformer-inference-under-1-millisecond-latency-e1be0057a51c&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML app design</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-ml-app-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-ml-app-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;build-and-deploy-data-science-products--a-practical-guide-to-building-a-machine-translation-application&#34;&gt;Build and Deploy Data Science Products : A Practical Guide to Building a Machine Translation Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey is going to be a 8 steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this series we will take a use case, understand the solution landscape and its evolution, 
explore different architecture choices, look under the hood of the architecture to understand the nuts and bolts, 
build a prototype, convert the prototype into production ready code, build an application from the production ready code 
and finally understand the process for deploying the application .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/build-your-machine-translation-application-byte-by-byte/&#34;&gt;Understand the landscape of solutions available for machine translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/ii-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-exploring-sequence-to-sequence-architecture-for-machine-translation/&#34;&gt;Explore sequence to sequence model architecture for machine translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/iii-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-looking-under-the-hood-of-machine-translation-model-lstm-forward-propagation/&#34;&gt;Deep dive into the LSTM model with worked out numerical example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/iv-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-looking-under-the-hood-of-machine-translation-model-lstm-backpropagation/&#34;&gt;Understand the back propagation algorithm for a LSTM model worked out with a numerical example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/v-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-machine-translation-application-develop-the-prototype/&#34;&gt;Build a prototype of the machine translation model using a Google colab / Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/vi-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-machine-translation-application-from-prototype-to-production-introduction-to-the-factory-model/&#34;&gt;Build the production grade code for the training module using Python scripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/vii-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-machine-translation-application-from-prototype-to-production-for-inference-process/&#34;&gt;Building the Machine Translation application -From Prototype to Production : Inference process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bayesianquest.com/2020/10/24/viii-build-and-deploy-data-science-products-machine-translation-application-build-and-deploy-using-flask/&#34;&gt;Build the machine translation application using Flask and understand the process to deploy the application on Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODELZOO</title>
      <link>/post/12021-11-14-modelzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/12021-11-14-modelzoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://modelzoo.co/frameworks&#34;&gt;Browse Frameworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://modelzoo.co/categories&#34;&gt;Browse Categories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision-Store - Computer Vision models with tutorials</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-vision-store-computer-vision-models-with-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-vision-store-computer-vision-models-with-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;AI Vision model store&amp;rdquo;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.augmentedstartups.com/visionstore&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are the Best, Regularly Updated Machine Learning Blogs or Resources Available?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-what-are-the-best-regularly-updated-machine-learning-blogs-or-resources-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-what-are-the-best-regularly-updated-machine-learning-blogs-or-resources-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neptune.ai/blog/the-best-regularly-updated-machine-learning-blogs-or-resources&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss> 
