<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nlp on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nlp on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flask Web App for Automatic Text Summarization Using SBERT</title>
      <link>/post/2022-02-27-a-flask-web-app-for-automatic-text-summarization-using-sbert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-02-27-a-flask-web-app-for-automatic-text-summarization-using-sbert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we will build a Flask web app that can input any long piece of information such as a blog or news article and summarize it into just five lines!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text summarization is an NLP(Natural Language Processing) task. SBERT(Sentence-BERT) has been used to achieve the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the article, you will learn how to integrate AI models and specifically pre-trained BERT models with Flask web technology as well! I will be explaining the step-by-step implementation right from the setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2022/02/a-flask-web-app-for-automatic-text-summarization-using-sbert/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph for Job Search Using BERT</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will build a job recommendation and skill discovery script that will take unstructured text as input, and will then output job recommendations and skill suggestions based on entities such as skills, years of experience, diploma, and major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will extract entities and relations from job descriptions using the BERT model and we will attempt to build a knowledge graph from skills and years of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/06/knowledge-graph-job-search-bert.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Knowledge Graph with Neo4J and Transformers</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to build a knowledge graph from job descriptions using fine-tuned transformer-based Named Entity Recognition (NER) and spacy’s relation extraction models. The method described here can be used in any different field such as biomedical, finance, healthcare, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below are the steps we are going to take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load our fine-tuned transformer NER and spacy relation extraction model in google colab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Neo4j Sandbox and add our entities and relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Query our graph to find the highest job match to a target resume, find the three most popular skills and highest skills co-occurrence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/11/build-knowledge-graph-neo4j-transformers.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Deploy a Simple Sentiment Analysis App via API</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FastAPI might be able to help. FastAPI is FastAPI is a web framework for building APIs with Python. We will use FastAPI in this article to build a REST API to service an NLP model which can be queried via GET request and can dole out responses to those queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example, we will skip the building of our own model, and instead leverage the Pipeline class of the HuggingFace Transformers library. Transformers is full of SOTA NLP models which can be used out of the box as-is, as well as fine-tuned for specific uses and high performance. The library&amp;rsquo;s pipelines can be summed up as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipelines are a great and easy way to use models for inference. These pipelines are objects that abstract most of the complex code from the library, offering a simple API dedicated to several tasks, including Named Entity Recognition, Masked Language Modeling, Sentiment Analysis, Feature Extraction and Question Answering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Transformers library, FastAPI, and astonishingly little code, we are going to create and deploy a very simple sentiment analysis app. We will also see how extending this same approach to a more complex app would be quite straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kdnuggets.com/2021/06/create-deploy-sentiment-analysis-app-api.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visual Guide to Using BERT for the First Time</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-a-visual-guide-to-using-bert-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-a-visual-guide-to-using-bert-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a simple tutorial for how to use a variant of BERT to classify sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example that is basic enough as a first intro, yet advanced enough to showcase some of the key concepts involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jalammar.github.io/a-visual-guide-to-using-bert-for-the-first-time/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fine-tune BERT to classify your Slack chats without coding</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-how-to-fine-tune-bert-to-classify-your-slack-chats-without-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-how-to-fine-tune-bert-to-classify-your-slack-chats-without-coding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;images/lifecycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack chats can become messy with time, proving difficult to extract meaningful information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I want to present a quick codeless way of fine-tuning and deploying the commonly used BERT classifier to do conversational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use that system to extract tasks, facts, and other valuable information from our Slack conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be easily extended for categorizing any other textual data, like support requests, emails, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/how-to-finetune-bert-to-classify-your-slack-chats-without-coding-3a7002936bcf&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss> 
