<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A collective list of APIs. Build</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-a-collective-list-of-apis-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-a-collective-list-of-apis-build/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A high-level plotting API for the PyData ecosystem built on HoloViews.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-a-high-level-plotting-api-for-the-pydata-ecosystem-built-on-holoviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-a-high-level-plotting-api-for-the-pydata-ecosystem-built-on-holoviews/</guid>
      <description>hvPlot provides a high-level plotting API built on HoloViews that provides a general and consistent API for plotting data in all the abovementioned formats. hvPlot can integrate neatly with the individual libraries if an extension mechanism for the native plot APIs is offered, or it can be used as a standalone component. To get started jump straight into the installation instructions and check out the current functionality in the User Guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful database diagrams</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-beautiful-database-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-beautiful-database-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful database diagrams
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a modern data architecture on AWS with Amazon AppFlow, AWS Lake Formation, and Amazon Redshift</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-build-a-modern-data-architecture-on-aws-with-amazon-appflow-aws-lake-formation-and-amazon-redshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-build-a-modern-data-architecture-on-aws-with-amazon-appflow-aws-lake-formation-and-amazon-redshift/</guid>
      <description>The following diagram illustrates the data platform architecture
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Bored Ape Yacht Club with Next.js, Tailwind &amp; Thirdweb (NFT Drop Tutorial)</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-build-bored-ape-yacht-club-with-next-js-tailwind-thirdweb-nft-drop-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-build-bored-ape-yacht-club-with-next-js-tailwind-thirdweb-nft-drop-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be building the BAYC Clone, an NFT Drop Tutorial using Next.JS, Tailwind and Thirdweb
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS25 I Stanford Seminar</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-cs25-i-stanford-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-cs25-i-stanford-seminar/</guid>
      <description>Since their introduction in 2017, transformers have revolutionized Natural Language Processing (NLP). Now, transformers are finding applications all over Deep Learning, be it computer vision (CV), reinforcement learning (RL), Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs), Speech or even Biology. Among other things, transformers have enabled the creation of powerful language models like GPT-3 and were instrumental in DeepMind&amp;rsquo;s recent AlphaFold2, that tackles protein folding.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databolt Flow</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-databolt-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-databolt-flow/</guid>
      <description>For data scientists and data engineers, d6tflow is a python library which makes building complex data science workflows easy, fast and intuitive. It is primarily designed for data scientists to build better models faster. For data engineers, it can also be a lightweight alternative and help productionize data science models faster. Unlike other data pipeline/workflow solutions, d6tflow focuses on managing data science research workflows instead of managing production data pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databolt Pipeline</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-databolt-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-databolt-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>d6tpipe is a python library which makes it easier to exchange data files. It&amp;rsquo;s like git for data! But better because you can include it in your data science code.
Link
Documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion Models and Score-matching Models</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-diffusion-models-and-score-matching-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-diffusion-models-and-score-matching-models/</guid>
      <description>This repository contains a collection of resources and papers on Diffusion Models and Score-matching Models.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Puzzles</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-gpu-puzzles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-gpu-puzzles/</guid>
      <description>GPU architectures are critical to machine learning, and seem to be becoming even more important every day. However you can be an expert in machine learning without ever touching GPU code. It is a bit weird to be work always through abstraction.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Systems Design Interview Guide</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-ml-systems-design-interview-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-ml-systems-design-interview-guide/</guid>
      <description>One of the trickiest interview rounds for ML practitioners is ML systems design. If you’re applying to be a Data Scientist, ML Engineer or ML Manager at a big tech company, you’ll probably face an ML Systems design question. I recently tackled this question at a few big tech companies on my way to becoming a Staff ML Engineer at Pinterest. In this article I’m going to talk about how to approach ML Systems Design interviews, core concepts to know and I’ll provide links to some of the resources I used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native EKS Ingress: AWS Load Balancer Controller &amp; 5 Examples (Terraform, TLS, IngressGroup, IP)</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-native-eks-ingress-aws-load-balancer-controller-5-examples-terraform-tls-ingressgroup-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-native-eks-ingress-aws-load-balancer-controller-5-examples-terraform-tls-ingressgroup-ip/</guid>
      <description>AWS Load Balancer Controller is a controller to help manage Elastic Load Balancers for a Kubernetes cluster.
Youtube
Tutorials</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public APIs</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-public-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-public-apis/</guid>
      <description>A collective list of free APIs for use in software and web development
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templating your SQL Queries Using Jinga on dbt</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-templating-your-sql-queries-using-jinga-on-dbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-templating-your-sql-queries-using-jinga-on-dbt/</guid>
      <description>DBT(data build tool) is a data transformation tool that enables data engineers and analysts to transform and document data. It provides the transformation layer in ELT(export-load-transform) process. It also facilitates how data professionals can build scalable and maintainable code just like software engineers.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensor Puzzles</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-tensor-puzzles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-tensor-puzzles/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of 16 tensor puzzles. Like chess puzzles these are not meant to simulate the complexity of a real program, but to practice in a simplified environment. Each puzzle asks you to reimplement one function in the NumPy standard library without magic.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definitive Guide to Building a Data Mesh With Event Streams</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-the-definitive-guide-to-building-a-data-mesh-with-event-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-the-definitive-guide-to-building-a-data-mesh-with-event-streams/</guid>
      <description>The data mesh concept is often presented with scant details regarding an implementation. We have created an opinionated prototype showcasing the principles of data mesh.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top ten cloud GPU platforms for deep learning</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-top-ten-cloud-gpu-platforms-for-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-top-ten-cloud-gpu-platforms-for-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we explore the services of available cloud GPU platforms with a focus on relevant factors such as pricing, infrastructure, design, performance, support, and security. We use this to present the best platforms to consider for your cloud GPU necessities.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform your data with dbt and Serverless architecture</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-transform-your-data-with-dbt-and-serverless-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-transform-your-data-with-dbt-and-serverless-architecture/</guid>
      <description>We recommend starting with the default structure created by the dbt init [TD1] command and checking out the best practices from the folks at dbt (dbt documentation, dbt app reference, and discourse).
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an awesome list? </title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-24-what-is-an-awesome-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-24-what-is-an-awesome-list/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Usage For a Machine Learning Workflow - Databolt Flow</title>
      <link>/post/2022-07-17-example-usage-for-a-machine-learning-workflow-databolt-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-07-17-example-usage-for-a-machine-learning-workflow-databolt-flow/</guid>
      <description>For data scientists and data engineers, d6tflow is a python library which makes building complex data science workflows easy, fast and intuitive. It is primarily designed for data scientists to build better models faster. For data engineers, it can also be a lightweight alternative and help productionize data science models faster. Unlike other data pipeline/workflow solutions, d6tflow focuses on managing data science research workflows instead of managing production data pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
