<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Are You Still Using Pandas to Process Big Data in 2021?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-are-you-still-using-pandas-to-process-big-data-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-are-you-still-using-pandas-to-process-big-data-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Dask provides advanced parallelism for analytics, enabling performance at scale for the tools you love. This includes numpy, pandas and sklearn. It is open-source and freely available. It uses existing Python APIs and data structures to make it easy to switch between Dask-powered equivalents.
Vaex is a high-performance Python library for lazy Out-of-Core DataFrames (similar to Pandas), to visualize and explore big tabular datasets. It can calculate basic statistics for more than a billion rows per second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Knowledge Graph for Job Search Using BERT</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-building-a-knowledge-graph-for-job-search-using-bert/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we will build a job recommendation and skill discovery script that will take unstructured text as input, and will then output job recommendations and skill suggestions based on entities such as skills, years of experience, diploma, and major.
We will extract entities and relations from job descriptions using the BERT model and we will attempt to build a knowledge graph from skills and years of experience.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Google Analytics Realtime Data with Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-exploring-google-analytics-realtime-data-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-exploring-google-analytics-realtime-data-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Take full advantage of all the Google Analytics features and data using its REST API and Python
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Machine Learning with Python Part 1: Basics, Metrics, and Algorithms</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-1-basics-metrics-and-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-1-basics-metrics-and-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to networks via key metrics and algorithms on a Football dataset
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Machine Learning with Python Part 2: Random Graphs and Diffusion Models of CryptoPunks Trading</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-2-random-graphs-and-diffusion-models-of-cryptopunks-trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-graph-machine-learning-with-python-part-2-random-graphs-and-diffusion-models-of-cryptopunks-trading/</guid>
      <description>Simulating and modeling the CryptoPunks trading data via a graph
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Knowledge Graph with Neo4J and Transformers</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-build-a-knowledge-graph-with-neo4j-and-transformers/</guid>
      <description>How to build a knowledge graph from job descriptions using fine-tuned transformer-based Named Entity Recognition (NER) and spacy’s relation extraction models. The method described here can be used in any different field such as biomedical, finance, healthcare, etc.
Below are the steps we are going to take:
  Load our fine-tuned transformer NER and spacy relation extraction model in google colab
  Create a Neo4j Sandbox and add our entities and relations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Deploy a Simple Sentiment Analysis App via API</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-create-and-deploy-a-simple-sentiment-analysis-app-via-api/</guid>
      <description>FastAPI might be able to help. FastAPI is FastAPI is a web framework for building APIs with Python. We will use FastAPI in this article to build a REST API to service an NLP model which can be queried via GET request and can dole out responses to those queries.
For this example, we will skip the building of our own model, and instead leverage the Pipeline class of the HuggingFace Transformers library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to process a DataFrame with millions of rows in seconds?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-process-a-dataframe-with-millions-of-rows-in-seconds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-how-to-process-a-dataframe-with-millions-of-rows-in-seconds/</guid>
      <description>Terality is a Serverless Data Processing Engine that processes the data in the Cloud. There is no need to manage infrastructure as Terality takes care of scaling compute resources. Its target audiences are Engineers and Data Scientists.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huberman Lab</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-huberman-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-huberman-lab/</guid>
      <description>PODCAST EPISODES
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the square root of two? | The Fundamental Theorem of Galois Theory</title>
      <link>/post/2021-12-04-what-is-the-square-root-of-two-the-fundamental-theorem-of-galois-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-12-04-what-is-the-square-root-of-two-the-fundamental-theorem-of-galois-theory/</guid>
      <description>This video is an introduction to Galois Theory, which spells out a beautiful correspondence between fields and their symmetry groups.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark Monitoring: How to Use Spark API and Open Source Libraries to Get Better Data Observability of Your Application</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-24-apache-spark-monitoring-how-to-use-spark-api-and-open-source-libraries-to-get-better-data-observability-of-your-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-24-apache-spark-monitoring-how-to-use-spark-api-and-open-source-libraries-to-get-better-data-observability-of-your-application/</guid>
      <description>See how to use Listener APIs and data quality libraries to get different levels of data observability for Apache Spark.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gartner Top Strategic Technology Trends for 2022</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-24-gartner-top-strategic-technology-trends-for-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-24-gartner-top-strategic-technology-trends-for-2022/</guid>
      <description>Gartner expects these 12 technology trends to act as force multipliers of digital business and innovation over the next three to five years. Here’s your quick guide to what the technologies are and why they’re valuable.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Metaflow</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</guid>
      <description>Metaflow is a human-friendly Python library that helps scientists and engineers build and manage real-life data science projects. Metaflow was originally developed at Netflix to boost the productivity of data scientists who work on a wide variety of projects from classical statistics to state-of-the-art deep learning.
Metaflow provides a unified API to the infrastructure stack that is required to execute data science projects, from prototype to production.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Python Tools You Need to Try</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-3-python-tools-you-need-to-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-3-python-tools-you-need-to-try/</guid>
      <description>Mito — A spreadsheet interface for Python Lux — Automated Visualization Suggestions and Generation Bokeh — Create Interactive Visualizations in Python Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Intuitive Guide To Transfer Learning </title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-a-complete-intuitive-guide-to-transfer-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 10:42:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-a-complete-intuitive-guide-to-transfer-learning/</guid>
      <description>Advancements in deep learning have been rapid over the past decade.
While the discovery of neural networks happened almost six decades ago with the invention of the first artificial neural network in 1958 by psychologist Frank Rosenblatt (called the &amp;ldquo;perceptron&amp;rdquo;), the developments in the field did not gain true popularity until about a decade ago.
The most popular achievement in 2009 was the creation of ImageNet. ImageNet is a humungous visual dataset that has led to some of the best modern-day deep learning and computer vision projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 &#43; Data Science, Deep Learning, AI &amp; Machine Learning Cheat Sheet PDF</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-100-data-science-deep-learning-ai-machine-learning-cheat-sheet-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-100-data-science-deep-learning-ai-machine-learning-cheat-sheet-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Anomaly Detection with Autoencoders</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-a-gentle-introduction-to-anomaly-detection-with-autoencoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-a-gentle-introduction-to-anomaly-detection-with-autoencoders/</guid>
      <description>Anomagram is an interactive visualization tool for exploring how a deep learning model can be applied to the task of anomaly detection (on stationary data).
Given an ECG signal sample, an autoencoder model (running live in your browser) can predict if it is normal or abnormal.
To try it out, click any of the test ECG signals from the ECG5000 dataset below, or better still, draw a signal to see the model&amp;rsquo;s prediction!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Production Level Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-a-guide-to-production-level-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-a-guide-to-production-level-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Deploying deep learning models in production can be challenging, as it is far beyond training models with good performance.
Several distinct components need to be designed and developed in order to deploy a production level deep learning system (seen below):
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visual Guide to Using BERT for the First Time</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-a-visual-guide-to-using-bert-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-a-visual-guide-to-using-bert-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>This post is a simple tutorial for how to use a variant of BERT to classify sentences.
This is an example that is basic enough as a first intro, yet advanced enough to showcase some of the key concepts involved.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome production machine learning</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-15-awesome-production-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-15-awesome-production-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>This repository contains a curated list of awesome open source libraries that will help you deploy, monitor, version, scale, and secure your production machine learning.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
