<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous GPT-4: From ChatGPT to AutoGPT, AgentGPT, BabyAGI, HuggingGPT, and Beyond</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-autonomous-gpt-4-from-chatgpt-to-autogpt-agentgpt-babyagi-hugginggpt-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-autonomous-gpt-4-from-chatgpt-to-autogpt-agentgpt-babyagi-hugginggpt-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>Emerging task automation and AI agents with GPT-4 after LangChain and LlamaIndex integration trend
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Managing an Isolation Forest Anomaly Detection Pipeline with Kedro</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-building-and-managing-an-isolation-forest-anomaly-detection-pipeline-with-kedro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-building-and-managing-an-isolation-forest-anomaly-detection-pipeline-with-kedro/</guid>
      <description>Anomaly (fraud) detection pipeline on credit card transaction data using Isolation Forest machine learning model and Kedro framework
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building LLM applications for production</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-building-llm-applications-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-building-llm-applications-for-production/</guid>
      <description>Building LLM applications for production
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating GPT-Driven Applications Using LangChain</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-creating-gpt-driven-applications-using-langchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-creating-gpt-driven-applications-using-langchain/</guid>
      <description>Large Language Models (LLMs) like OpenAI ChatGPT are called foundational models because even though they are trained for a relatively small set of tasks, they work exceptionally well for multiple unseen downstream tasks. While there is still some debate on how they are so good, at a high level it is quite easy to under what they do — they just predict the next word (read tokens). And all the cool tools you see built using these models, are nothing but the smart application of this feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Insights from Text Data inside Databases using OpenAI GPT-3 and MindsDB integration</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-extract-insights-from-text-data-inside-databases-using-openai-gpt-3-and-mindsdb-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-extract-insights-from-text-data-inside-databases-using-openai-gpt-3-and-mindsdb-integration/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you have a lot of text data inside your database. And you want to extract insights to analyze it or perform various AI tasks on text data. In this article, you will learn how to use MindsDB to integrate your database with OpenAI GPT-3 and get insights from all your text data at once with a few SQL commands instead of making multiple individual API calls, ETL-ing and moving massive amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance NLP 1.5.0 is out!</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-finance-nlp-1-5-0-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-finance-nlp-1-5-0-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Finance NLP is a John Snow Lab’s product, launched 2022 to provide state-of-the-art, autoscalable, domain-specific NLP on top of Spark. With more than 100 models, featuring Deep Learning and Transformer-based architectures
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with semantic workflows</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-getting-started-with-semantic-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-getting-started-with-semantic-workflows/</guid>
      <description>A guide on when to use small and large language models
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Neo4j into the LangChain ecosystem</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-integrating-neo4j-into-the-langchain-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-integrating-neo4j-into-the-langchain-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to develop a LangChain agent that has multiple ways of interacting with the Neo4j database
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Retrieval Architecture for LLM’s (2023)</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-knowledge-retrieval-architecture-for-llm-s-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-knowledge-retrieval-architecture-for-llm-s-2023/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, I share my analysis of the current architectural best practices for data-informed language model applications. This particular subdiscipline is experiencing phenomenal research interest even by the standards of large language models - in this guide, I cite 8 research papers and 4 software projects, with a median initial publication date of November 22nd, 2022.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LLM as a Chatbot Service</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-llm-as-a-chatbot-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-llm-as-a-chatbot-service/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this repository is to let people to use lots of open sourced instruction-following fine-tuned LLM models as a Chatbot service. Because different models behave differently, and different models require differently formmated prompts, I made a very simple library Ping Pong for model agnostic conversation and context managements.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML System Design Doc - Reliable ML</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-ml-system-design-doc-reliable-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-ml-system-design-doc-reliable-ml/</guid>
      <description>ML System Design Doc
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDFGPT.IO</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-pdfgpt-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-pdfgpt-io/</guid>
      <description>PDFGPT.IO
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantra</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-semantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-semantra/</guid>
      <description>Semantra is a multipurpose tool for semantically searching documents. Query by meaning rather than just by matching text.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text2Diagram</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-text2diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-text2diagram/</guid>
      <description>Text2Diagram: Create schematic architecture diagrams, UML, flowcharts, Gnatt charts, mind maps, Sequence diagrams, User Journey and many more with natural language.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practical Guides for Large Language Models</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-the-practical-guides-for-large-language-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-the-practical-guides-for-large-language-models/</guid>
      <description>A curated (still actively updated) list of practical guide resources of LLMs. It&amp;rsquo;s based on our survey paper: Harnessing the Power of LLMs in Practice: A Survey on ChatGPT and Beyond and efforts from @xinyadu. The survey is partially based on the second half of this Blog. We also build an evolutionary tree of modern Large Language Models (LLMs) to trace the development of language models in recent years and highlights some of the most well-known models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WizardLM: An Instruction-following LLM Using Evol-Instruct</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-23-wizardlm-an-instruction-following-llm-using-evol-instruct/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-23-wizardlm-an-instruction-following-llm-using-evol-instruct/</guid>
      <description>At present, our core contributors are preparing the 65B version and we expect to empower WizardLM with the ability to perform instruction evolution itself, aiming to evolve your specific data at a low cost.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Open Source Data Exploration Tools You Need to Know in 2023</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-15-11-open-source-data-exploration-tools-you-need-to-know-in-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-15-11-open-source-data-exploration-tools-you-need-to-know-in-2023/</guid>
      <description>There are many well-known libraries and platforms for data analysis such as Pandas and Tableau, in addition to analytical databases like ClickHouse, MariaDB, Apache Druid, Apache Pinot, Google BigQuery, Amazon RedShift, etc. While machine learning frameworks and platforms like PyTorch, TensorFlow, and scikit-learn can perform data exploration well, it’s not their primary intent. There are also plenty of data visualization libraries available that can handle exploration like Plotly, matplotlib, D3, Apache ECharts, Bokeh, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To HuggingFace Transformers for NLP</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-15-an-introduction-to-huggingface-transformers-for-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-15-an-introduction-to-huggingface-transformers-for-nlp/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will be covering what HuggingFace is, how and why it came to exist, and how to best utilize it for your machine learning workflows. We&amp;rsquo;ll also touch on the different use cases covered by the various HuggingFace packages in the ecosystem.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Feature Engineering in Python</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-15-automated-feature-engineering-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-15-automated-feature-engineering-in-python/</guid>
      <description>A guide to augmenting your dataset with new and informative features using Upgini
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Agents &amp; Agent Simulations</title>
      <link>/post/2023-07-15-autonomous-agents-agent-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2023-07-15-autonomous-agents-agent-simulations/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two weeks, there has been a massive increase in using LLMs in an agentic manner. Specifically, projects like AutoGPT, BabyAGI, CAMEL, and Generative Agents have popped up. The LangChain community has now implemented some parts of all of those projects in the LangChain framework. While researching and implementing these projects, we’ve tried to best understand what the differences between them are and what the novel features of each are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
