<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A community maintained Python library for creating mathematical animations.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-a-community-maintained-python-library-for-creating-mathematical-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-a-community-maintained-python-library-for-creating-mathematical-animations/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A general-purpose programmatic animation tool</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-a-general-purpose-programmatic-animation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-a-general-purpose-programmatic-animation-tool/</guid>
      <description>A gallery of animations made with Morpho is available here. For more, you can also take a look at the YouTube channels Morphocular and Serpentine Integral, which use Morpho to create most of the animations.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome AI Guidelines</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-awesome-ai-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-awesome-ai-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>This repository aims to simplify this by mapping the ecosystem of guidelines, principles, codes of ethics, standards and regulation being put in place around artificial intelligence.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Realtime Chat App with Django Channels and WebSockets</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-building-a-realtime-chat-app-with-django-channels-and-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-building-a-realtime-chat-app-with-django-channels-and-websockets/</guid>
      <description>Building stateful web applications can be tricky, unless you use a framework, of course—Django to the rescue! In this article, learn how to build a realtime chat app using Django Channels and WebSockets.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building makemore Part 3: Activations &amp; Gradients, BatchNorm</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-building-makemore-part-3-activations-gradients-batchnorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-building-makemore-part-3-activations-gradients-batchnorm/</guid>
      <description>We dive into some of the internals of MLPs with multiple layers and scrutinize the statistics of the forward pass activations, backward pass gradients, and some of the pitfalls when they are improperly scaled. We also look at the typical diagnostic tools and visualizations you&amp;rsquo;d want to use to understand the health of your deep network. We learn why training deep neural nets can be fragile and introduce the first modern innovation that made doing so much easier: Batch Normalization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS197 Harvard: AI Research Experiences</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-cs197-harvard-ai-research-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-cs197-harvard-ai-research-experiences/</guid>
      <description>Once we go from training one model to training hundreds of different models with different hyperparameters, we need to start organizing. We’re going to break down our organization into three pieces: experiment tracking, hyperparameter search, and configuration setup.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How diffusion models work: the math from scratch</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-how-diffusion-models-work-the-math-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-how-diffusion-models-work-the-math-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Diffusion models are a new class of state-of-the-art generative models that generate diverse high-resolution images. They have already attracted a lot of attention after OpenAI, Nvidia and Google managed to train large-scale models. Example architectures that are based on diffusion models are GLIDE, DALLE-2, Imagen, and the full open-source stable diffusion.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>skopeo is a command line utility that performs various operations on container images and image repositories.</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-skopeo-is-a-command-line-utility-that-performs-various-operations-on-container-images-and-image-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-skopeo-is-a-command-line-utility-that-performs-various-operations-on-container-images-and-image-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Skopeo works with API V2 container image registries such as docker.io and quay.io registries, private registries, local directories and local OCI-layout directories.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneaky REST APIs With Django Ninja</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-sneaky-rest-apis-with-django-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-sneaky-rest-apis-with-django-ninja/</guid>
      <description>Many web projects have moved to the single-page application model. To use this model with Django, you build a project where Django is the back end accessed through a REST API. The Django Ninja library is a FastAPI-inspired tool kit for turning Django views into REST API endpoints with very little extra code. Along the way, you’ll be using curl, a command-line tool that allows you to grab the contents of a web page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacetimeformer Multivariate Forecasting</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-spacetimeformer-multivariate-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-spacetimeformer-multivariate-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Spacetimeformer is a Transformer that learns temporal patterns like a time series model and spatial patterns like a Graph Neural Network.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>These are all the youtube videos from the Summer of Math Exposition 2</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-these-are-all-the-youtube-videos-from-the-summer-of-math-exposition-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-these-are-all-the-youtube-videos-from-the-summer-of-math-exposition-2/</guid>
      <description>Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer learning for Time Series Forecasting</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-transfer-learning-for-time-series-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-transfer-learning-for-time-series-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Transfer learning refers to the process of pre-training a flexible model on a large dataset and using it later on other data with little to no training. It is one of the most outstanding 🚀 achievements in Machine Learning 🧠 and has many practical applications.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is dstack?</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-16-what-is-dstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-16-what-is-dstack/</guid>
      <description>dstack is a lightweight and open-source command-line tool to provision infrastructure for ML workflows.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate All the Boring Kubernetes Operations with Python</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-automate-all-the-boring-kubernetes-operations-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-automate-all-the-boring-kubernetes-operations-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes became a de-facto standard in recent years and many of us - both DevOps engineers and developers alike - use it on daily basis. Many of the task that we perform are however, same, boring and easy to automate. Oftentimes it&amp;rsquo;s simple enough to whip up a quick shell script with a bunch of kubectl commands, but for more complicated automation tasks bash just isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, and you need the power of proper language, such as Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandit Algorithms</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-bandit-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-bandit-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Multi-armed bandits have now been studied for nearly a century. While research in the beginning was quite meandering, there is now a large community publishing hundreds of articles every year. Bandit algorithms are also finding their way into practical applications in industry, especially in on-line platforms where data is readily available and automation is the only way to scale.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Reactive Data Streaming App with Python and Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-build-a-reactive-data-streaming-app-with-python-and-apache-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-build-a-reactive-data-streaming-app-with-python-and-apache-kafka/</guid>
      <description>How do you get live notifications from a service that doesn’t support live notifications? Can you watch an online store for price drops? Or track comments on someone else’s YouTube video? Or at work, can you react to changes in another
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DALL·E Now Available Without Waitlist</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-dall-e-now-available-without-waitlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-dall-e-now-available-without-waitlist/</guid>
      <description>New users can start creating straight away. Lessons learned from deployment and improvements to our safety systems make wider availability possible. Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Memos</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-data-memos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-data-memos/</guid>
      <description>12 reflections on data (and its representation) that we don’t want to forget in the “next-normal”
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Neural Network for Recommender System</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-graph-neural-network-for-recommender-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-graph-neural-network-for-recommender-system/</guid>
      <description>Recently, graph neural network (GNN) has become the new state-of-the-art approach in many recommendation problems, with its strong ability to handle structured data and to explore high-order information.	However, as the recommendation tasks are diverse and various in the real world, it is quite challenging to design proper GNN methods for specific problems. In this tutorial, we focus on the critical challenges of GNN-based recommendation and the potential solutions.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>labml.ai Annotated PyTorch Paper Implementations</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-01-labml-ai-annotated-pytorch-paper-implementations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-10-01-labml-ai-annotated-pytorch-paper-implementations/</guid>
      <description>This is a collection of simple PyTorch implementations of neural networks and related algorithms. These implementations are documented with explanations, and the website renders these as side-by-side formatted notes. We believe these would help you understand these algorithms better.
Link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
