<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>libraries on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/tags/libraries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in libraries on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/libraries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph-based Fraud Detection Papers and Resources</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-21-graph-based-fraud-detection-papers-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-21-graph-based-fraud-detection-papers-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A curated list of fraud detection papers using graph information or graph neural networks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/safe-graph/graph-fraud-detection-papers&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch VAE</title>
      <link>/post/2022-03-21-pytorch-vae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-03-21-pytorch-vae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A collection of Variational AutoEncoders (VAEs) implemented in pytorch with focus on reproducibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project is to provide a quick and simple working example for many of the cool VAE models out there. All the models are trained on the CelebA dataset for consistency and comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture of all the models are kept as similar as possible with the same layers, except for cases where the original paper necessitates a radically different architecture (Ex. VQ VAE uses Residual layers and no Batch-Norm, unlike other models). Here are the results of each model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AntixK/PyTorch-VAE&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Useful Examples of Python’s itertools</title>
      <link>/post/2022-02-19-7-useful-examples-of-python-s-itertools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2022-02-19-7-useful-examples-of-python-s-itertools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Python itertools library is provides extremely useful utility functions for dealing with iterables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By becoming fluent in the itertools functions, you can combine them in new ways and use them as building blocks for tackling complex problems in very few lines of code. In this article, you will see 7 practical examples of the applications of itertools functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/7-useful-examples-of-pythons-itertools-e561dc9f15ca&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss> 
