<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automl on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</title>
    <link>/tags/automl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automl on If you torture the data long enough, it will confess ©</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/automl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Metaflow</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-24-what-is-metaflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Metaflow is a human-friendly Python library that helps scientists and engineers build and manage real-life data science projects. Metaflow was originally developed at Netflix to boost the productivity of data scientists who work on a wide variety of projects from classical statistics to state-of-the-art deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metaflow provides a unified API to the infrastructure stack that is required to execute data science projects, from prototype to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.metaflow.org/introduction/what-is-metaflow&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bento ML</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-bento-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-bento-ml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BentoML is a flexible, high-performance framework for serving, managing, and deploying machine learning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports Multiple ML frameworks, including Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, XGBoost and more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud native deployment with Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure and many more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-Performance online API serving and offline batch serving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web dashboards and APIs for model registry and deployment management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.bentoml.org/en/latest/index.html&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Deploying a Machine Learning Model on Vertex AI using Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Write ML Pipelines that will make your MLOps team happy: follow a clean separation of responsibility between model code and ops code. This article show you how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/developing-and-deploying-a-machine-learning-model-on-vertex-ai-using-python-865b535814f8&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EvalML</title>
      <link>/post/2021-11-14-evalml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-11-14-evalml/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EvalML is an AutoML library which builds, optimizes, and evaluates machine learning pipelines using domain-specific objective functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Functionality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automation - Makes machine learning easier. Avoid training and tuning models by hand. Includes data quality checks, cross-validation and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data Checks - Catches and warns of problems with your data and problem setup before modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-to-end - Constructs and optimizes pipelines that include state-of-the-art preprocessing, feature engineering, feature selection, and a variety of modeling techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model Understanding - Provides tools to understand and introspect on models, to learn how they&amp;rsquo;ll behave in your problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domain-specific - Includes repository of domain-specific objective functions and an interface to define your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss> 
